A Guide to the Whisner Memorial Methodist Church Records, 1857-1975
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Whisner Memorial Methodist Church Records, 1857-1975
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1964-003
4.0 cu. ft. 5 boxes
Collection consists of records generated by the Methodist Church located in Blacksburg, Virginia from 1857 through 1975.
Whisner Memorial Methodist Church. (Blacksburg, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Whisner Memorial Methodist Church Records were donated to the Special Collections
Historical Information
The Methodist Church of Blacksburg, Virginia was formally organized in the late eighteenth-century. Following the construction of a new building in 1906, members named the structure the Whisner Memorial Methodist Church after Reverend P. H. Whisner, a popular local minister who died a few months prior to the completion of the building which bears his name.
Scope and Content
Collection contains church registers, bulletins, recording steward's book, financial reports, treasurer's book, quarterly conference minutes, Sunday school records, the Women's Foreign Missionary Service records, and the Women's Society of Christian Service records.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Whisner Memorial Methodist Church. (Blacksburg, Va.)
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.)
Contents List
- Budgetary Materials, 1927-1972 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Bulletins,1946-1975
  - 6/16/1946-10/30/1955 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - 11/6/1955-9/15/1957 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - 9/22/1957-3/29/1959 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - 4/5/1959-5/28/1961 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - 6/4/1961-8/18/1963 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - 9/1/1963-5/23/1965 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - 5/30/1965-12/24/1967 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - 1/7/1968-2/15/1970 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - 2/22/1970-8/13/1972 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - 9/17/1972-4/20/1975 (Box-folder 1:11)
- List of Pastors, 1859-1943 (Box-folder 1:12)
- Monthly Individual Account Book, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 1:13)
- Newsletters, 1953-1973 (Box-folder 1:14)
- Quarterly Conference Records, 1880-1948
  - 1880-1888 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - 1888-1896 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - 1896-1902 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - 1902-1910 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - 1910-1915 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - 1915-1923 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - 1923-1931 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - 1931-1939 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - 1939-1941 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - 1941-1944 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - 1944-1948 (Box-folder 2:11)
- Record of Baptisms, 1857-1870 (Box 5)
- Registers, 1878-1938
  - 1878-1893 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - 1895-1917 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - 1917-1929 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - 1927-1938 (Box-folder 3:2)
- Recording Steward's Book, 1859-1880 (Box-folder 3:6)
- Sermons, 1966, n.d. (Box-folder 3:7)
- Sunday School Records, 1879-1913
  - 1879-1882 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - 1886-1888 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - 1889-1891 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - 1892-1893 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - 1894-1896 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - 1901-1913 (Box-folder 3:13)
- Women's Foreign Missionary Service, 1905-1910 (Box-folder 4:1)
- Women's Society of Christian Service (WSCS), Record and Report Book, 1941-1960
  - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - 1943-1946 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - 1947-1948 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - 1949-1950 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - 1951-1954 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - 1954-1960 (Box-folder 4:8)
- Women's Society of Christian Service (WSCS) Reports, 1941-1964 (Box-folder 4:3)